<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strategy on N9O</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/strategy/</link><description>Recent content in Strategy on N9O</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2024 Nuno Coração</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Execution is King</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202403-execution-is-king/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202403-execution-is-king/</guid><description>As a Product Manager, more often than not, I notice people mixing up ideation and execution phases in discussions. Both when evaluating new initiatives to bet on and when evaluating what is happening in their industry.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202403-execution-is-king/feature.webp"/></item><item><title>Evolution of AI and Amara's Law</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202401-evolution-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202401-evolution-ai/</guid><description>We tend to overestimate the effect of a technology in the short run and underestimate the effect in the long run.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202401-evolution-ai/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Product-Market Fit: What it is and do you have it</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202307-pmf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202307-pmf/</guid><description>In the fast-paced and competitive world of entrepreneurship, achieving product-market fit (PMF) is the holy grail. It is the moment when a product or service aligns perfectly with the needs and desires of the target market, leading to enthusiastic customer adoption and sustainable growth. But how do entrepreneurs know if they have truly achieved this elusive state?</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202307-pmf/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>Blitzscaling</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202304-blitzscalling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202304-blitzscalling/</guid><description>Blitzscaling is a term coined by entrepreneur and investor Reid Hoffman, which refers to a strategy for rapidly scaling up a company in a short period. The idea behind blitzscaling is to prioritize growth over profitability, aiming to dominate a market and become a category leader. While blitzscaling can lead to significant success for companies, it also has some significant downsides.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202304-blitzscalling/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>How to Develop an Effective Strategy</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202302-how-to-develop-a-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202302-how-to-develop-a-strategy/</guid><description>Most people consider strategy to be an event, some magical moment that changes the course of a company and defines its success for generations. The tale goes, some smart people get together (or occasionally one solo genius), they decide what they are going to do, and then they start implementing that strategy. That&amp;rsquo;s actually not the way the world works.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202302-how-to-develop-a-strategy/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>How to Structure Product Teams</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202301-how-to-structure-product-teams/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202301-how-to-structure-product-teams/</guid><description>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you work in a startup, scale-up, or a larger organization, in any case, the success of a product team usually equals growing such a team. These changes bring challenges and opportunities to organizations. Here are some strategies for organizing product teams, what they optimize, and in which situation to use them.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202301-how-to-structure-product-teams/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>The New Artificial Intelligence Hype</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202210-the-new-ai-hype/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202210-the-new-ai-hype/</guid><description>In the last few years, the hype around artificial intelligence has been increasing (again). Most of it is due to truly groundbreaking research and innovative showcases in the field. From machines winning complex games like Go and Dota 2, to various content generation techniques, these technologies will impact our future.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202210-the-new-ai-hype/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>Apple: iPhone 14, Watch 8, and Sustaining Innovation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202209-apple-sustaining-innovation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202209-apple-sustaining-innovation/</guid><description>On the 7th of September, Apple held its “Far Out” iPhone event. New iPhones, Apple Watches, and AirPods were announced, each coming with a plethora of features. Yes, all of it was innovation, but none of it brought the kind of excitement Apple used to. Why is that? And why probably this is the best strategy for Apple.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202209-apple-sustaining-innovation/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>Streaming Wars and What Comes After…</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202209-streaming-wars/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202209-streaming-wars/</guid><description>Last July and for the first time ever, streaming viewership surpassed cable. The streaming wars began around 2010 when Netflix introduced their first streaming-only plan with no DVD rentals, other players laughed at the time… little did they know. A decade after, there’s a multitude of streaming services available for mainstream entertainment and also for specific niches. What will happen next?</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202209-streaming-wars/feature.jpg"/></item><item><title>The Future of the Nintendo Switch</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/202109-the-future-of-nintendo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/202109-the-future-of-nintendo/</guid><description>Nintendo achieved something truly amazing with the launch of the Switch. It was able to disrupt itself and the entire gaming industry while saving itself from doom. How exactly was Nintendo able to do it and what comes next in that story?</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/posts/202109-the-future-of-nintendo/feature.jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>